<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 13:23:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The 5 benefits of selling digital products online</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 13:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Magali Ferber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19568</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Games, ebooks, movies, music, graphic designs and computer applications&#8211;these are just a few of the things you can now purchase online as digital products. We’ve invited Jimena Diaz de Vivar, owner of the PrestaShop store Dulzura de papel, to share her experience selling graphic design templates for themed party printables such as invitations, posters, napkins [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/">The 5 benefits of selling digital products online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Games, ebooks, movies, music, graphic designs and computer applications&#8211;these are just a few of the things you can now purchase online as digital products. We’ve invited Jimena Diaz de Vivar, owner of the PrestaShop store <a href="http://dulzuradepapel.com/" target="_blank">Dulzura de papel</a>, to share her experience selling graphic design templates for themed party printables such as invitations, posters, napkins and food presentation details.<br />
Read the five benefits she shared with us if you’re considering selling your digital creations online&#8211;it might just be the perfect move for your business.<br />
<span id="more-19568"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">Unlimited Stock</h2>
<p>Digital products have the unique advantage of never going “out of stock.” As long as a customer is interested in buying the product, you have a chance to make the sale.</p>
<p>But this doesn’t mean your products will last forever; they eventually become obsolete, just like any other product. For example, Jimena updates graphic designs for her online shop every season to reflect new trends. It’s important to keep refreshing your product selection and stay up to date with your customers’ needs.</p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">Low Costs</h2>
<p>Inventory costs can be as high as 75% of a product’s retail price. However, if you create your digital product on your own&#8211; let’s say you write a book and then sell it online&#8211;your inventory cost drops to $0. This significantly decreases the cost of starting your online store.</p>
<p>However, decreasing the cost of your inventory isn’t the only way you can save money. Without physical inventory, you also eliminate costs like shipping, storage and warehouse management.</p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">International Markets</h2>
<p>Unlike physical products, digital products don’t have barriers such as customs or shipping restrictions. When you sell downloadable products, it doesn’t matter how far away your customers are&#8211;you can reach anyone anywhere as long as they have internet access. “You can reach millions of potential customers that are thousands of kilometers away from you,” says Jimena.</p>
<p>International and domestic orders are very similar. Jimena says, “PrestaShop simplifies selling internationally, with geo-localization by IP addresses to adjust your shop’s currencies and multi-language pages with their corresponding payment methods; everything is done for you!”</p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">Flexible Work Schedule</h2>
<p>Owning your own business certainly gives you a lot of freedom. But when you sell physical products, you are automatically limited by your office’s location and hours of operation. For example, when a sale comes through, orders must be picked up, packed and labeled before the end of the business day to ensure timely shipping.</p>
<p>Digital goods don’t have these limitations. You can set your own schedule and work whenever and wherever you want. A customer’s order is virtually “shipped” to them, automatically. This is all possible with an automated system, which leads us to the next benefit.</p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">Automated System</h2>
<p>The PrestaShop software can be configured so that products are emailed or available for download automatically after each purchase. All merchants have to do is ensure the system is working properly. “What motivated me to create Dulzura de Papel was the flexibility I could have with an online store. Once everything is set up and the store functions well, you’re done. Products get sold on their own,” says Jimena.</p>
<h2 style="color: #b23485">Key takeaways</h2>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Never run out of stock with digital goods</li>
<li>Benefit from lower inventory, shipping and warehouse costs</li>
<li>Reach international markets with less hassle</li>
<li>Work wherever and whenever you want</li>
<li>Automated functions make selling easier</li>
</ul>
<p>Are you ready to start selling digital products online with PrestaShop? Check out <a href="http://www.matthewwoodward.co.uk/tutorials/sell-digital-products-online-prestashop/" target="_blank">this tutorial video series</a> created by Matthew Woodward. The series will walk you through the entire process of setting up your own digital online shop.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/">The 5 benefits of selling digital products online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Must-Have Features in a great Payment Processor</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-features-great-payment-processor/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-features-great-payment-processor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 13:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As more and more customers being shopping online, ecommerce websites have popped up to support those shoppers. From monthly subscription boxes to homemade products, all types of online shops have opened. And with each shop that opens, a new need is created – one for industry related services. Payment processing is one example of those [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-features-great-payment-processor/">3 Must-Have Features in a great Payment Processor</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As more and more customers being shopping online, ecommerce websites have popped up to support those shoppers. From monthly subscription boxes to homemade products, all types of online shops have opened. And with each shop that opens, a new need is created – one for industry related services. <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/hardeepwalia/2012/11/21/black-friday-puts-payment-processing-stocks-into-focus/" target="_blank">Payment processing</a> is one example of those services. Today there are countless payment processors to choose from. But how do you know what to look for? To help you narrow down your options, we share the 3 must-have features in a great payment processor.</p>
<p><span id="more-19576"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #f69000"><a style="text-decoration: underline;color: #f69000;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;font-weight: bold" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-uncovers-future-mobile-commerce/" target="_blank">Mobile Optimized</a> Payment Page</h2>
<p>Did you know that in 2012, <a href="http://www.mobilecommercedaily.com/2012/07/10/mobile-payment-use-nearly-doubles-in-a-year-report" target="_blank">34% of mobile owners</a> made a purchase using their mobile device? It shows that mobile customers are not only browse and research products, but make and complete purchases. To convert these on-the-go shoppers, you need a mobile-optimized payment page.</p>
<p>If your payment processor hosts your payment page, be sure that the design on the page matches your website. It should include your logo, featured colors and carry the same voice.</p>
<h2 style="color: #f69000">Integrated <a style="text-decoration: underline;color: #f69000;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;font-weight: bold" href="http://www.realexpayments.com/images/resources/Fraud_Management.pdf" target="_blank">Fraud Prevention Tools</a></h2>
<p>Fraud can take many forms but for online merchants, the most common type is chargebacks from unauthorized credit card use. Chargebacks hurt your shop because you take a loss for the product you shipped, must refund the original amount charged, and pay chargeback fees.</p>
<p>It’s why great payment processors offer a free suite of fraud prevention tools. They are security features that ensure shoppers are the authorized users for the credit card. Great payment processors have a combination or all of the following:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>3D Secure</strong> – more popularly known as Verified by Visa, Mastercard SecureCode and American Express Safekey. It allows payment processors to verify a cardholder’s identity through a separate passcode associated with the customer’s card.</li>
<li><strong>Transactional Screening</strong> – compares translation data like IP addresses against your whitelisted and backlisted customers.</li>
<li><strong>Data Sanity Checking</strong> – compares certain fields in the transaction against other fields, such as billing versus shipping addresses.</li>
<li><strong>Data Pattern Checking</strong> – reviews data in your transaction against previous transactions</li>
<li><strong>Card Verification Number (CVN)</strong> – verifies the 3 digit number on the back of the card matches with the issuing bank.</li>
<li><strong>Address Verification Service (AVS)</strong> – Verifies billing information with the issuing bank.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #f69000"><a style="text-decoration: underline;color: #f69000;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;font-weight: bold" href="http://www.realexpayments.com/images/resources/Recurring_Payments.pdf" target="_blank">Recurring Billing</a> or Recurring Payments</h2>
<p>This feature provides you with a safe and secure way to store your customer’s payment information. Letting customers to save their credit card information is a must have for every store because it allows you to:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Rebill customers for products or your services automatically</li>
<li>Save time spent on invoicing and billing, reducing payment processing costs</li>
<li><strong>Increase conversion for impulse purchases</strong> – Once customers add product to their shopping cart, the checkout process is streamlined. It’s effortless for customers to go from I want to I bought.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #f69000"><strong>Bonus!</strong> Great Customer Service</h2>
<p>We’ve added great customer service to this list as a bonus because it’s not quite a feature but is just as important. When selecting a payment provider, it’s important keep in mind that this is a long term relationship. Make sure they offer your preferred form of communication. For example, if you like speaking to customer service agents over the phone, check to see they offer phone support. The same goes for language. Ensure you can get help in a language you speak.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Looking for a payment processor that has all these must-haves features? Check out PrestaShop partner, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/8943-realexredirect.html">Realex Payments</a>, a company processing over €28 billion annually for over 12,500 online retailers, across 30 countries, including some of the world’s leading brands – Vodafone, Aer Lingus and Virgin Atlantic. In addition to having each feature in our must-have list, they also offer:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>A responsive hosted payment page</li>
<li>Dynamic currency conversion</li>
<li>Proprietary fraud scoring and pattern analysis tool</li>
<li>Detailed transaction logs</li>
<li>Customizable sub-account rules.</li>
</ul>
<p>Learn more by <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/realex-payments">visiting our website</a> or jump right in and start accepting online payments by <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/8943-realexredirect.html">downloading their module</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-features-great-payment-processor/">3 Must-Have Features in a great Payment Processor</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-features-great-payment-processor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 Google Analytics Ecommerce Dashboards</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-google-analytics-ecommerce-dashboards/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-google-analytics-ecommerce-dashboards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 13:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kunle Campbell (Guest Contributor)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19590</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Google Analytics offers a treasure trove of traffic and conversion data geared to helping you better understand onsite shopping behavior, traffic referrals and conversions in your store. But getting the most out of this data requires some organization. One of my favorite tools to retrieve insights quickly and clearly is ‘Dashboards’. Today I’m going to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-google-analytics-ecommerce-dashboards/">8 Google Analytics Ecommerce Dashboards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google Analytics offers a treasure trove of traffic and conversion data geared to helping you better understand onsite shopping behavior, traffic referrals and conversions in your store. But getting the most out of this data requires some organization. One of my favorite tools to retrieve insights quickly and clearly is ‘Dashboards’. Today I’m going to introduce you to 8 of my favorite dashboards.<br />
<span id="more-19590"></span></p>
<h4 style="color: #ff9900">Get a handle on online store performance with dashboards</h4>
<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-19591" style="text-align: center" alt="GA" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/0.GA_.png" width="275" height="336" /></p>
<p>Sifting through all your data to get to the most important traffic and conversion metrics is easy with Google Analytics’ Dashboards. They’re basically a collection of fully-customizable widgets that provide a quick glimpse into the most relevant report summaries right from your Google Analytics account.</p>
<p>Dashboards enable ecommerce managers and marketers to:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>View metrics and reports regularly</li>
<li>Share reports with key stakeholders – like your board, marketing team or CEO</li>
<li>View reports with the flexibility to change date ranges and segments</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that Google Analytics Dashboards:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Support a maximum of 12 widgets (boxes) per report</li>
<li>Are limited to a maximum of 10 rows per widget</li>
<li>Gives each Analytics account an allowance of 20 dashboards.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are 8 highly-recommended Dashboards specific to ecommerce and available free of charge from <a href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.type%3DDASHBOARD%26_.start%3D0/" target="_blank">Google Analytics’ Solution Gallery</a>:</p>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3DfJa880IAQseTLF0SddcsmQ" target="_blank">1. Ecommerce Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Blast Analytics &amp; Marketing</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19592" alt="Ecommerce Dashboard By Blast Analytics Marketing" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/1.-Ecommerce-Dashboard-By-Blast-Analytics-Marketing-1024x522.png" width="700" height="356" /></p>
<p>This dashboard is a great point of reference at the start of a work week or at the end of the month. It summaries key metrics such as:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Visits</li>
<li>Visits and product revenue by mobile (including tablet)</li>
<li>Visits and product revenue by source / medium</li>
<li>Ecommerce conversion rates</li>
<li>Total revenue</li>
<li>Transactions</li>
<li>Average order value</li>
<li>Per visit value</li>
<li>Top 10 products by revenue</li>
</ul>
<p>It enables you to track performance as well as understand top-converting traffic channels and best-selling products.</p>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3D8USYBWAaQ5eDjl_XaKeLmQ" target="_blank">2. Mobile Ecommerce Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Justin Cutroni</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19593" alt="Mobile Ecommerce Dashboard  By Justin Cutroni" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/2.-Mobile-Ecommerce-Dashboard-By-Justin-Cutroni--1024x552.png" width="700" height="377" /></p>
<p>If you want to understand mobile visitor behavior, this Dashboard will give you the insight you need.<br />
Its widgets include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Revenue from mobile traffic</li>
<li>Top performing mobile campaigns (requires UTM tagging)</li>
<li>Organic keywords from mobile devices</li>
<li>Bounce rate vs Average session</li>
<li>Top pages from mobile devices</li>
<li>Mobile revenue and Average order value (AOV)</li>
<li>Top products purchased from mobile devices</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3DoMS4jWBURDG4J9RakRx5-Q" target="_blank">3. Ecommerce SEO Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Vagelis Varfis | Nudge Digital</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19601" alt="Ecommerce SEO Dashboard" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/3.-Ecommerce-SEO-Dashboard-1024x602.png" width="700" height="411" /></p>
<p>Ecommerce SEOs will love this keyword-focused dashboard. But bear in mind that 80-90 per cent of the time, organic SEO keyword traffic is ‘not provided”, so the keyword data provided here is based on a sample size. In order to get more complete insights, it’s best to use this data in combination with Google Webmaster Tools.</p>
<p>In addition to 4 widgets dedicated to traffic and revenue, this dashboard includes helpful SEO- specific widgets such as:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Search engines leading to transactions (non brand)</li>
<li>Traffic sources leading to transactions (non brand)</li>
<li>Revenue generating non-brand organic keywords (requires configuration)</li>
<li>Non-brand organic search keywords with the highest Average Order Value (requires configuration)</li>
<li>Most popular non brand organic search terms</li>
<li>Internal search terms that have generated revenue</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3DijKy1DMRQSuqjek-w4WfHQ" target="_blank">4. [DP6] Paid Search Campaigns</a></h2>
<p>By Thiago Doin (@thiagodoin)</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19594" alt="[DP6] Paid Search Campaigns  By Thiago Doin (@thiagodoin)" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/4.-DP6-Paid-Search-Campaigns-By-Thiago-Doin-@thiagodoin--1024x540.png" width="700" height="369" /></p>
<p>This dashboard is great for tracking AdWords performance at a single glance. Originally produced in Portuguese, you can display labels in any language. Widgets include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Revenue from AdWords</li>
<li>AdWords spend</li>
<li>Transactions, CPA &amp; conversions</li>
<li>Visits from AdWords</li>
<li>Top 10 regions that made purchases via AdWords</li>
<li>Top 10 products purchased via AdWords</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3D9pw2EKPSRBqpVQ2iMcoB1g" target="_blank">5. Traffic Growth Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Cemal Buyukgokcesu</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19595" alt="Engagement &amp; Loyalty Dashboard, Traffic Growth Dashboard  By Cemal Buyukgokcesu" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/5.-Engagement-Loyalty-Dashboard-Traffic-Growth-Dashboard-By-Cemal-Buyukgokcesu--1024x548.png" width="700" height="374" /></p>
<p>The traffic growth dashboard gives a complete picture of traffic performance.<br />
Widgets report:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Data on visits</li>
<li>Active visitors</li>
<li>Traffic sources</li>
<li>Traffic sources by geography</li>
<li>Mobile OS traffic breakdown (iOS, Android or Windows)</li>
<li>Traffic by mobile device</li>
<li>Top 10 referring domains</li>
<li>Top 10 social referrals.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3DerNMqvwYQIWKDiA7dkHbJQ" target="_blank">6. Social Media Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Justin Cutroni</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19596" alt="Social Media Dashboard By Justin Cutroni" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/6.-Social-Media-Dashboard-By-Justin-Cutroni--1024x550.png" width="700" height="375" /></p>
<p>This dashboard provides a quick snapshot of traffic from social media referral. Its most insightful widgets are:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>On site social media actions</li>
<li>Value of social media traffic</li>
<li>Social media traffic from mobile devices</li>
<li>Revenue and per visit value from social media</li>
<li>Social traffic that ‘read an article’</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3DpONDBX8LSseVK2Zq-WdVMw" target="_blank">7. Email Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Blast Analytics &amp; Marketing</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19597" alt="Email Dashboard By Blast Analytics &amp; Marketing" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/7.-Email-Dashboard-By-Blast-Analytics-Marketing--1024x561.png" width="700" height="383" /></p>
<p>This dashboard is indispensable if you use email marketing to drive sales to your store (which you should!). The most useful widgets provide critical data about email marketing traffic such as:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Email marketing revenue (based on last interaction attribution)</li>
<li>Bounce rate of email traffic &#8211; to help track the effectiveness of your email copy and landing page</li>
<li>A landing page report from email traffic only</li>
<li>A country performance report &#8211; which you can change to ‘region’ if you only sell within a country</li>
<li>Top revenue generating products via email marketing</li>
<li>And if you UTM tag links in your email campaigns (which you should!), a widget provides a “top 10 email campaign” performance report</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #068cc9"><a style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma, Verdana, sans-serif;font-size: 28px;color: #068cc9;text-decoration: underline" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/gallery/#posts/search/%3F_.viewId%3D0iewn0tTTZ2dpJq3LNQwtA" target="_blank">8. All-in-one Ecommerce Dashboard</a></h2>
<p>By Paolo Margari</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19598" alt="All-in-one Ecommerce Dashboard By Paolo Margari" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/8.-All-in-one-Ecommerce-Dashboard-By-Paolo-Margari--1024x547.png" width="700" height="373" /></p>
<p>Last but not least, the All-in-One Ecommerce Dashboard by Paolo Margari is an easy to understand dashboard that can be presented to non-technical stakeholders on your team, like your CEO or the board of directors.</p>
<p>Here’s a summary of its simple and straightforward widgets:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Unique number of visitors (users) or transactions</li>
<li>Number of transactions</li>
<li>Ecommerce conversion rate</li>
<li>Total Revenue</li>
<li>Average Order Value (<span style="font-style: italic">AOV</span>)</li>
<li>Revenue breakdown by Device: <span style="font-style: italic">desktop, tablet and mobile</span></li>
<li>Transaction and Conversion Rate breakdown by Device: <span style="font-style: italic">desktop, tablet and mobile</span></li>
<li>Transaction by City</li>
<li>Ecommerce Conversion rates by Medium and Device</li>
<li>Transactions by Medium</li>
<li>Sources and medium of revenue generating traffic</li>
<li>Transactions and ecommerce conversion rate by Source / Medium</li>
</ul>
<p>On a final note, my advice for getting the most out of these dashboards is to always <a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1033867?hl=en-GB" target="_blank">UTM tag your campaigns</a>, as it enables medium and campaign sources to be tracked and reported accurately.</p>
<p>Do you use dashboards? Let us know your favorites.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-google-analytics-ecommerce-dashboards/">8 Google Analytics Ecommerce Dashboards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-google-analytics-ecommerce-dashboards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>February Staff Picks: 3 Free and Lovely Features to Help You Sell More</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/february-staff-picks-3-free-lovely-features-help-sell/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/february-staff-picks-3-free-lovely-features-help-sell/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19553</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Is your shop ready for Valentine’s Days sales? If you’ve read our blog post titled, “10 Valentine’s Day ecommerce marketing ideas”, you’re probably all set. But are you sure? Ecommerce is booming industry that adapts quickly, giving merchants access to new features added regularly. Today we share with you three new and FREE PrestaShop modules. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/february-staff-picks-3-free-lovely-features-help-sell/">February Staff Picks: 3 Free and Lovely Features to Help You Sell More</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19557" style="margin: 0" alt="staff picks" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/staff-picks-1.png" width="200" height="155" /></p>
<p>Is your shop ready for Valentine’s Days sales? If you’ve read our blog post titled, “<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/" target="_blank">10 Valentine’s Day ecommerce marketing ideas</a>”, you’re probably all set.</p>
<p>But are you sure? Ecommerce is booming industry that adapts quickly, giving merchants access to new features added regularly. Today we share with you three new and FREE PrestaShop modules. From marketing to payments, these come pre-integrated within your PrestaShop back-office, or are available for free at our Addons Marketplace. Check them out!</p>
<p>You’ll find more about:</p>
<p><strong style="color: #99cc00">LoyaltyLion</strong> - Create your loyalty program in minutes and keep customers coming back.<br />
<strong style="color: #99cc00">Olark</strong> – Provide customer service through chat to increase sales.<br />
<strong style="color: #99cc00">VT Payments</strong> – Reach over 1 billion cardholders  with over 4.5 billion UnionPay cards across 8 different currencies.<br />
<span id="more-19553"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #008000">LoyaltyLion</h2>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/18684-olark.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19554" alt="loyaltylion" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/loyaltylion.jpeg" width="282" height="240" /></a></p>
<p style="font-style: italic;text-align: center">REWARD CUSTOMERS FOR REFERING FRIENDS AND OTHER ONSITE ACTIVITIES</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">What it does:</strong> LoyaltyLion makes it easy for you to reward customers for making purchases, leaving reviews, creating an account, referring friends or simply visiting the website. Assign the number of points to reward for each activity and the voucher amounts that correspond. LoyaltyLion keeps track of the points customers collect and redeem.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">Why we love it:</strong> This not only helps you understand the behavior of your best customers, but it also makes them happy. Discover your most engaged customers, top spenders and biggest advocates. Use this information to retain key customers and personalize your communications.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">How it helps you sell more:</strong> Acquire new customers using the refer-a-friend feature. In two clicks your customers can refer their friends on Facebook, Twitter and via email. LoyaltyLion then tracks the success of these referrals. You’ll be able to see the revenue generated, new customers acquired and users who are referring and many more. Best of all, you engage your customers, inviting them to come back to earn more points.</p>
<p class="text-center" style="font-style: italic"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/18137-loyaltylion.html" target="_blank">Start your free 14 day trial.</a><br />
Or activate it directly through your PrestaShop Back Office &gt; Modules &gt; Advertising and Marketing</p>
<h2 style="color: #008000">Olark</h2>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/18684-olark.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19555" alt="olark" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/olark.jpeg" width="282" height="240" /></a></p>
<p style="font-style: italic;text-align: center">CONNECT TO CUSTOMERS BY ANSWERING QUESTIONS INSTANTLY VIA LIVE CHAT</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">What it does:</strong> Olark adds a tab at the bottom corner of every page of your online store encouraging customers to reach out if they have any questions. It also tracks customer interaction and summarizes the information on a user-friendly dashboard.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">Why we love it:</strong> Their comprehensive help center has everything you need to set up and get started with live chat. From how-to videos and in-depth product descriptions to weekly webinars, you will have endless resources at your fingertips. Olark also provides one-on-one help by chat during your on-boarding process, to make sure you are fully comfortable with all the functionalities it has to offer.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">How it helps you sell more:</strong> Chatting live with customers is an easy way to solve three common challenges merchants face: better understanding the customer, upselling to increase average orders. By instantly addressing customer question, you decrease turnover by making shopping easy for customers.</p>
<p class="text-center" style="font-style: italic"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/18684-olark.html" target="_blank">Download the Free Module from PrestaShop Addons</a><br />
Or activate it directly through your PrestaShop Back Office &gt; Modules &gt; Front Office Features</p>
<h2 style="color: #008000">VT Payment</h2>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/17682-vtpayment.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19556" alt="VT-Payment" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/VT-Payment.jpg" width="282" height="240" /></a></p>
<p style="font-style: italic;text-align: center">SELL ACROSS MULTIPLE ASIAN COUNTRIES WITH ONE PAYMENT SOLUTION</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">What it does:</strong> VT Payment allows you to accept payments across many Asian countries through the UnionPay Online technology. They provide, efficient settlement, easy PrestaShop integration, fast registrations, and support multiple currencies.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">Why we love it:</strong> With just one module, you open your online shop’s doors to customers across a wider range of countries by accepting their preferred choice of currency. You don’t have to open a new account with each country you want to target, it is an all-in-one module that will make expanding your shop easier.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #ed2279">How it helps you sell more:</strong> You can accepts the following currencies: USD, CNY (China), IDR (Indonesia), KRW (Korea), AUD (Australia), NZD (New Zealand), TWD (Taiwan), HKD (Hong Kong), and MOP (Macau). Opening up your shop to all these currencies and countries gives you exposure to  millions of potential customers, especially customers from China.</p>
<p class="text-center" style="font-style: italic"><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/17682-vtpayment.html" target="_blank">Download the Free Module from PrestaShop Addons</a><br />
Or activate it directly through your PrestaShop Back Office &gt; Modules &gt; Payments</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/february-staff-picks-3-free-lovely-features-help-sell/">February Staff Picks: 3 Free and Lovely Features to Help You Sell More</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/february-staff-picks-3-free-lovely-features-help-sell/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Knock out Google Panda: SEO best practices for PrestaShop</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today we welcome back Jordi Ordóñez, a PrestaShop Community member (jordiob) and owner of Barcelona-based website http://jordiob.com/. As an ecommerce consultant, he advises merchants on ecommerce practices, web development and search engine optimization. Today he shares his advice for SEO on ecommerce websites. After a long break from writing on PrestaShop’s blog, I’m happy to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/">Knock out Google Panda: SEO best practices for PrestaShop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we welcome back <a href="https://plus.google.com/101848022626876111829/about" target="_blank">Jordi Ordóñez</a>, a PrestaShop Community member (<a style="font-style: italic" href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/user/145757-jordiob/" target="_blank">jordiob</a>) and owner of Barcelona-based website <a href="http://jordiob.com/" target="_blank">http://jordiob.com/</a>. As an ecommerce consultant, he advises merchants on ecommerce practices, web development and search engine optimization. Today he shares his advice for SEO on ecommerce websites.<br />
<span id="more-19487"></span></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19488" style="margin-right: 0" alt="Jordi Ordóñez" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/Jordi-Ordóñez.jpg" width="235" height="207" /></p>
<p>After a long break from writing on PrestaShop’s blog, I’m happy to have the opportunity to talk about PrestaShop and SEO again. Today we’re going to focus on Google Panda penalizations and how to avoid them.</p>
<p>Google initially released the Panda algorithm in February 2011. The goal of this algorithm was to penalize and kill low quality sites (websites with copy-pasted, low quality content and thin content) and drop their search engine rankings.</p>
<h2 style="color:#00933B">How do I know if my site is affected by Panda?</h2>
<p>I call Panda “the silent killer.” Unlike Google Penguin’s dramatic and instant traffic drop, Panda drops your organic traffic slowly. It’s why you need to closely monitor your organic traffic if you think it might be affecting you. Let’s take a look at a how Google’s Penguin and Panda penalties drop your web traffic:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19489" alt="Google panda vs Google penguin" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/Google-panda-vs-Google-penguin.png" width="560" height="273" /></p>
<p>As you can see, Penguin is an instant-killer, while Panda is a mid to long term traffic killer. You won’t notice a Panda penalty as quickly as a Penguin one, and by then it might be too late.</p>
<p>Because your traffic doesn’t dramatically drop from one day to another (only in extreme cases), you’ll need daily reports on organic traffic from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/analytics-stats-prestashop-modules/4168-ganalytics.html">Google Analytics</a> (or another tool). From an ecommerce standpoint, Penguin force you to close your online business faster than Panda might. Also, recovering from a Penguin hit is more complicated than recovering from a Panda penalization.</p>
<p>So, how can you tell if your site is affected? Watch out for drops in organic traffic, even small ones. It may be hard to detect because your organic traffic will show a slow down over several weeks.</p>
<p>My good friend and SEO consultant <a href="http://www.mjcachon.es/" target="_blank">MJ Cachon</a> has introduced me to some great free tools that you can use too: <a style="font-weight: bold" href="http://www.barracuda-digital.co.uk/panguin-tool/">Panguin</a>, <a style="font-weight: bold" href="http://feinternational.com/website-penalty-indicator/" target="_blank">Website Penalty Indicator</a> or <a style="font-weight: bold" href="http://suite.searchmetrics.com/en/research/domains/organic" target="_blank">SearchMetrics</a>.</p>
<p>Another powerful free tool is <a style="font-weight: bold" href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1033021?hl=en" target="_blank">Google Analytics alert</a> function. Set daily alerts to know at what rate your organic traffic is dropping each day.</p>
<h2 style="color:#00933B">So, what’s wrong with my PrestaShop store?</h2>
<p>Well, let’s see what baby Panda likes to eat (besides grass):</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Thin content</li>
<li>Poor content</li>
<li>Duplicated content</li>
<li>Massive 404 errors</li>
<li>Low quality links</li>
<li>Keyword stuffing</li>
<li>Content for search engines, not people</li>
<li>Page speed</li>
</ul>
<p>This is what’s at the core of Panda’s algorithm. But, in case you want to investigate in-depth how it works, Bill Slawski at SEO by the sea gives an explanation of the <a href="http://www.seobythesea.com/2014/09/new-panda-update-new-panda-patent/">patents developed and acquired by Google</a> make Panda what it is.</p>
<h2 style="color:#00933B">How can I rebound from the Panda Penalty?</h2>
<p>Find out how to fix your problems by asking and answering the questions below. Be honest: your traffic depends on it.</p>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">Do I have poor or thin content on my site?</h4>
<p>This is especially important on product and category pages as well as your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/content-marketing-for-ecommerce-technical-checklist-writing-process/">blog</a> (if you don’t have one, you should!). Keep in mind that search engines value content above all, so always create original, meaningful and useful content. Never copy-paste text provided by your distributor, wholesaler or manufacturer. <a href="http://siteliner.com/" target="_blank">Siteliner</a> is great tool to help you visualize overall content quality on your ecommerce site; it displays the percentage of duplicated, common and original content on your site.</p>
<p>If you need to fix large amounts of poor content and you’re already selling, with little time to spare, consider <a style="font-style: italic" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">hiring someone</a> to do it. Never&#8211;let me be clear here&#8211;NEVER trust cheap services for your content curation. If you’ve been hit by Panda, hiring someone that DOES NOT write useful and original stuff can lead you to a worst hit.</p>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">Do I have massive 404 errors on my site?</h4>
<p>Crawl your site using <a href="http://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/" target="_blank">Screamingfrog</a> or <a href="http://home.snafu.de/tilman/xenulink.html" target="_blank">Xenu</a> to check how many 404 errors you have and fix them. And, of course, use <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/2409439?hl=en" target="_blank">Google Webmaster Tools</a> to keep track of the 404 errors and use <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/93641?hl=en">Google guidelines</a> to create useful 404 pages. Be careful when deleting or deactivating products and categories on your shop. Always redirect expired products (with 301 redirects) to the parent category or to a similar product. Do the same with category pages.</p>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">Do I have low-quality links pointing to my website?</h4>
<p>Fixing this issue is more complicated, and finding a free tool to intensely evaluate backlink quality is difficult. I suggest using <a href="https://majestic.com/" target="_blank">Majestic</a>, <a href="https://ahrefs.com/" target="_blank">Ahrefs</a> or <a href="https://moz.com/researchtools/ose/" target="_blank">Moz’s Open Site Explorer</a> to make a first assessment and determine if your links are good or bad. If you think you have a serious problem, take action using the best tools: <a href="http://www.linkdetox.com/" target="_blank">Link Detox</a> and the Disavow Tool in Google Webmaster Tools. Two quick tips:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>If more than 5% of the links have the same exact keyword (let’s say: buy ebooks online) in the anchor text, you’ve been exposed! (Use Majestic’s free anchor text report to see if this is your case)</li>
<li>Avoid low-quality links like link farms and networks, footer links, blogrolls, link blocks, site-wide links, blog comments, forum comments, forum profile links and signatures, web directories and article directories.</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">Have I been keyword-stuffing my ecommerce website?</h4>
<p>Well, that’s an easy one. Have you been over-optimizing your PrestaShop pages by filling them with repeated keywords? If the answer is “yes” or “well… maybe,” then you did.</p>
<p>Start rewriting your pages with proper content. Do not repeat the same keyword more than 3 times per page, especially if your content is short. Google knows what you’re doing, so no more funny business!</p>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">Have I been writing content for search engines, not people?</h4>
<p>Another easy one. Have you been writing stuff for humans or robots? Again, if the answer is “yes” or “well… maybe,” then yes. Or do what I call the “mama test” &#8211; if your mama can’t understand what you’re writing about or what you’re selling, you’re better off rewriting that content. Remember, real people are buying your stuff, not Google.</p>
<h4 style="color:#3369E8">And last but not least: Is my page speed slower than a love song?</h4>
<p>If so, you need to improve it. Use the performance options under the preferences tab on your back office to speed up PrestaShop store. Next try reducing image sizes, moving your shop to a dedicated server, assessing your web server with the TTFB (Time to First Byte) metric, using Content Delivery Networks to reduce the average load time of images, CSS and JavaScript or even purchasing a caching module from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=cache">PrestaShop’s Addons Store</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color:#00933B">Bonus: Tips for PrestaShop websites</h2>
<p>Yes, I’m a proud PrestaShop user, and have been for the last 4 years. So I have hands on knowledge of how PrestaShop works. Here are some additional tips that might help you avoid an instant SEO death:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Keep your robots.txt healthy.</strong> Avoid EVERY non useful parameter, especially the ones created by the layered navigation module.</li>
<li><strong>Check your sitemap regularly</strong> and do not include non-useful pages such as cart, order, login, address, addresses, voucher, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Be careful when importing CSV files.</strong> Include the product creation date, otherwise products can be created in 1.969, which generates errors on Google Webmaster Tools’ sitemap.</li>
<li><strong>Be careful when creating CDN subdomains.</strong> Sometimes (when not created properly), they duplicate the content, so double and triple check it.</li>
<li><strong>Always speed up your site</strong> once it’s live, use the <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/" target="_blank">Google Page Speed</a> tool and <a href="http://gtmetrix.com/" target="_blank">GTMetrix.com</a> to create useful reports about what can be improved.</li>
</ul>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Is your website recovering from a Google penalty? Share how you overcame them in the comments below. Just starting your recovery? Tell us which tip you’re going to try first.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/">Knock out Google Panda: SEO best practices for PrestaShop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick and easy settings to speed up your PrestaShop store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 13:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19479</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>You’ve added all your products and put the finishing touches on your PrestaShop store design. Today is the day you take your store out of maintenance mode. You refresh your homepage but all you see is a blank page for 1… 2… 3… 4… whole seconds! As excited as you are, a question lingers at [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/">Quick and easy settings to speed up your PrestaShop store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve added all your products and put the finishing touches on your PrestaShop store design. Today is the day you take your store out of maintenance mode. You refresh your homepage but all you see is a blank page for 1… 2… 3… 4… whole seconds!</p>
<p>As excited as you are, a question lingers at the back of your mind: “Why did my online store take so long to load?”<br />
<span id="more-19479"></span><br />
It’s a question many merchants find themselves asking, and the answer is quite simple. The PrestaShop performance settings optimized for website development aren’t the same for page load speed. With PrestaShop, it’s easy to switch your shop’s configurations from development-friendly to speed-optimized. So today we share some quick and easy settings to speed up your PrestaShop store. As an added bonus, we explain how each setting works.</p>
<p>Start by logging into your PrestaShop back office, and navigating to ADVANCED PARAMETERS &gt; PERFORMANCE</p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">Smarty Tab</h2>
<p>There you’ll see the <strong>SMARTY</strong> tab, which corresponds to your theme or template. (<a href="http://www.smarty.net/" target="_blank">Smarty</a> is the template language used on PrestaShop themes.)</p>
<p><strong>Template Compilation:</strong> This setting determines whether the website has to recompile its instructions. Why does a theme have instructions? The PrestaShop default template is built to be flexible and customizable to meet the needs of any online merchant. With that said, our design elements are not static; each design module connects to your shop with its own set of template instructions. It’s how you can customize our default template to make it your own.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong>[X] Never recompile template files</strong> – (Fastest) Select this if you are completely satisfied with the design and are done editing files.<br />
<strong>[ ] Recompile templates if the files have been updated</strong> – (Fast) Choose this option if you’re a developer-merchant who makes regular theme edits to the website. The page will only recompile if changes have been made to theme files.<br />
<strong>[ ] Force compilation</strong> – (Slow) Only use this setting while you’re debugging the website. Each time the page loads, the theme re-determines which elements should be displayed and how.</p>
<p><strong>Cache:</strong> A <a href="http://searchstorage.techtarget.com/definition/cache" target="_blank">cache</a> refers to temporarily stored files that increase performance and reduce delays.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong>[X] YES</strong> – Once you’re done customizing your front office theme, turn on this option to improve your website’s performance for customers.<br />
<strong>[ ] NO</strong> – The only time you don’t use caching is when you’re actively working on your theme. If you don’t have this option disabled, you won’t see the changes you’ve made immediately. When you’re developing the theme, clear your cache to ensure the changes are reflected on the webpage.</p>
<p><strong>Caching Type: File System or MySQL</strong> – Because this setting’s configuration varies from shop to shop, there is no definitive answer when deciding which is better. It really depends on the size of your database, along with its configuration and optimization. If you have a small database, it’ll be difficult to notice any difference.</p>
<p><strong>Clear Cache:</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong>[ ] Never clear cache files</strong> – Select this option if you want to stop clearing the cache altogether. This is useful if you are doing a lot of modifications, or some bulk actions like a CSV import: you wouldn’t want the cache to be cleared constantly. Be sure to turn this option off when you are done; or clear your cache manually.<br />
<strong>[X] Clear cache every time something has been modified</strong> &#8211; It does exactly what it says. Your website’s cache will be cleared once something changes. This ensures your customers see the most updated version of your website.</p>
<p><strong>BONUS:</strong> If you want even more control over how often and which pages are cached, download our premium community developed <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/seo-prestashop-modules/6413-cache-manager.html" target="_blank">Cache Manager</a> from PrestaShop Addons.</p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">Optional Features</h2>
<p>Turning off the following features may speed up your website, but barely. They also limit PrestaShop’s features and restrict you from using the software to its full potential.<br />
Please note, if these options are grayed out and you can’t disable then, you’re already using the feature.</p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">CCC (Combine, Compress and Cache)</h2>
<p>CCC is a set of tools aimed at minimizing website loading time. Here’s what it does:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;font-style: italic">CCC combines similar text files into one bigger file, which limits the number of files to download; then compresses the file using the common Zip algorithm, which speeds downloads. Finally, it caches the compressed file, eliminating the need to perform this process each time a page loads, relieving the burden on the server&#8217;s processor.</p>
<p>Beware some of these settings may distort your theme, so be sure to turn them on one at time. And as always, be sure to test your website after making any changes.</p>
<p><strong>Smart cache for CSS: [YES]</strong> &#8211; Combine, compress and cache CSS type files.<br />
<strong>Smart cache for JavaScript*: [YES]</strong> &#8211; Combine, compress and cache JavaScript type files.<br />
<strong>Minify HTML: [YES]</strong> – This configuration removes all the white spaces in the HTML code generated from the Smarty Template.<br />
<strong>Compress inline JavaScript* in HTML: [YES]</strong> – If you’re using JavaScripts in your theme, compress them so they load faster.<br />
<strong>Move JavaScript* to the end: [YES]</strong> &#8211; Moving the JavaScript to the end forces it to load last, allowing your webpage to load the simpler elements of your website first.</p>
<p>*These settings affect JavaScript, which is used in theme development and can be distorted with these options.</p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">It’s your turn</h2>
<p>Ready to speed up your PrestaShop store? Here’s a snapshot of configurations for a lightening-fast load time.</p>
<div style="height: 400px"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-19480" alt="smarty" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/smarty_en.png" width="280" height="298" /><img class="alignleft  wp-image-19481" alt="ccc" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/ccc_en.png" width="248" height="378" /></div>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>To learn more about your online store’s advanced parameters, visit our <a style="font-weight: bold" href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Understanding+the+Advanced+Parameters" target="_blank">official online documentation</a>. Or if you’re running an older version of PrestaShop, search for your version in our <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/dashboard.action" target="_blank">documentation archives</a> then check out the original <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-best-tips-to-speed-up-your-prestashop-store-3/">blog post dedicated to helping you speed up your website</a>.</p>
<p>How much faster is your online shop loading with our recommended settings? Let us know your results in the comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/">Quick and easy settings to speed up your PrestaShop store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enter our eBusinessPlan Competition</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/enter-e-business-plan-competition/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/enter-e-business-plan-competition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 22:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Magali Ferber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19516</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Do you have what it takes to become the next ecommerce success story? Submit a business plan for your online store at ebusinessplan.prestashop.com for a chance to win a Golden Ticket to ecommerce success! If there’s a lesson to be learned about any business, it’s that success depends [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/enter-e-business-plan-competition/">Enter our eBusinessPlan Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><span style="line-height: 1.5">Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Do you have what it takes to become the next ecommerce success story?</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Submit a business plan for your online store at <strong><a href="http://ebusinessplan.prestashop.com" target="_blank">ebusinessplan.prestashop.com</a></strong> for a chance to win a Golden Ticket to ecommerce success!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-19516"></span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">If there’s a lesson to be learned about any business, it’s that success depends on having a powerful vision right from the start. This contest is designed to help you carry your vision all the way to success. We’ve put together a guide to help you build a complete </span>ecommerce<span style="line-height: 1.5"> business plan. Don’t panic! We’re not looking for a 30-page plan, just a brief summary that reflects the power of your idea and the values behind it.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5"><strong>You can do it!</strong> The most important thing is not to be afraid of taking a chance. We look forward to receiving </span>ecommerce<span style="line-height: 1.5"> business plans from all over the world, and we encourage you to send it in your native language if you feel more comfortable doing so.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">The 5 best eBusinessPlans will be awarded<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/support/18633-starter-pack-prestashop-cloud.html" target="_blank"><strong> PrestaShop Starter Packs</strong></a>. The visionary entrepreneur who wins this contest will have the opportunity to fully benefit from PrestaShop’s expertise in </span>ecommerce<span style="line-height: 1.5"> and a Gold Starter Pack that will help bring his or her eBusinessPlan to life through the creation of a successful online store hosted on PrestaShop Cloud.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">Are you ready to jump-start your business dreams? Rev your engine with our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/download/pdf/eBusinessPlanGuide-PrestaShop.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>eBusinessPlan Guide</strong></a>. And while you are at it, remember: the difference between ordinary and extraordinary is a little bit of “extra”.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">Best of luck,<br />
</span>The PrestaTeam</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="line-height: 1.5">P.S. Don’t forget to submit your <a href="http://ebusinessplan.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">eBusinessPlan </a><em>before</em> March 4th.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/enter-e-business-plan-competition/">Enter our eBusinessPlan Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/enter-e-business-plan-competition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to set up auto-recurring billing for your online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-auto-recurring-billing-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-auto-recurring-billing-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The scenario is common to new, startup businesses. A customer wants to sign up for a recurring service or products. You’re left wondering what the best solution would be to ensure they get charged in a timely, reliable manner. Like many small business owners, you don’t have the time to set a calendar remind to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-auto-recurring-billing-online-store/">How to set up auto-recurring billing for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The scenario is common to new, startup businesses. A customer wants to sign up for a recurring service or products. You’re left wondering what the best solution would be to ensure they get charged in a timely, reliable manner. Like many small business owners, you don’t have the time to set a calendar remind to ask for payment.</p>
<p>Instead, services like auto-recurring billing can be your best friend. With auto-recurring billing, you can automate your subscription reordering process so you never forget to bill customers again.</p>
<p>To provide you more importation on auto-recurring billing, we’ve turned to one of our online payment partners, Simplify Commerce about the basics of auto-recurring billing for online stores and how to set up auto-recurring billing using their free online payment module.<br />
<span id="more-19444"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #ff6e25">Why would I choose auto-recurring billing?</h2>
<p>Auto-recurring billing or subscription billing allows online merchants to automatically charge customers on a monthly basis for products or services. It’s a great win-win: customers regularly receive products or services; merchants never forget to bill their customers.</p>
<p>Some online merchants who’ve used auto-recurring billing include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 40px">
<li>Subscriptions boxes</li>
<li>Grocery delivery services</li>
<li>Cleaning services</li>
<li>Rent collection</li>
<li>Gym memberships</li>
<li>Pest control services</li>
<li>Book club subscriptions</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #ff6e25">How is auto-recurring billing different from up-front billing?</h2>
<p>Auto-recurring billing is great for merchants that provide a recurring service or have recurring shipments. Once auto-recurring billing is configured and scheduled, it practically runs by itself.</p>
<p>Up-front billing is great for merchants providing an on-and-done service or product. Products that fall into this category include furniture, clothing and digital goods. However, with the popularity of subscription boxes and services any online store can leverage auto-recurring billing.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ff6e25">How can online merchants prevent subscription cancellations?</h2>
<p>Although everything is automated, it’s important for business owners to engage with their customers. Use each order as a way to get in touch with your customers. Try sending emails to customers about the service or product they just received. Ask for reviews or encourage them to engage with you on social media. Is there a special holiday coming up? Surprise customers with a little treat to thank them for their continued subscription.</p>
<p>Want another tip for more sales? Increase conversions by including discount coupons in email newsletters.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ff6e25">How to get started today</h2>
<p>Setting up and managing auto-recurring billing is easy with Simplify Commerce. Set up in 5 simple steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Download Simplify Commerce from your PrestaShop Back office</li>
<li>Configure your Simplify Commerce module</li>
<li>Log into your Simplify platform</li>
<li>Click &#8220;+New Plan&#8221;</li>
<li>Enter the plan name, cost and the frequency, then click “Add Subscription.”</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color: #ff6e25">Sponsored by: Simplify Commerce</h2>
<p>Simplify Commerce, backed by MasterCard (a global leader in the payment industry for decades) is an all-in-one payment solution that enables businesses and non-profits to accept all major credit and debit cards. Their turnkey secure payments solution offers a simple, flat 2.85% + 30₵ rate with no extra fees. They also offer two business day funding and the highest Level 1 PCI Certification.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19449" alt="simplify commerce logo" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/02/simplify-commerce-logo.png" width="317" height="141" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-auto-recurring-billing-online-store/">How to set up auto-recurring billing for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-auto-recurring-billing-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce For Everyone</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-for-everyone/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-for-everyone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bruno Lévêque]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19494</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When I founded PrestaShop seven years ago, I had a singular vision for the company. My idea was to create a global community of talented individuals who love ecommerce. Tapping into the power of open source, we could change the industry with cutting edge software that enables everyone to participate in the ecommerce revolution. &#160; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-for-everyone/">Ecommerce For Everyone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-19495" alt="bleveque prestashop" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/bleveque-prestashop.jpg" width="170" height="203" align="left" /></p>
<p>When I founded PrestaShop seven years ago, I had a singular vision for the company. My idea was to create a global community of talented individuals who love ecommerce. Tapping into the power of open source, we could change the industry with cutting edge software that enables everyone to participate in the ecommerce revolution.</p>
<p><span id="more-19494"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/117911117" width="700" height="394" frameborder="0" title="Introducing PrestaShop - Ecommerce for everyone" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Today, you&#8217;re part of a 700,000+ member PrestaShop community and I&#8217;m truly thankful for your support.</p>
<p>I want to take this opportunity to make a special announcement that represents another ground-breaking achievement for all of us. Today marks <strong>the official launch of PrestaShop Cloud</strong>, a free fully-hosted version of our software. This is truly unprecedented in the market.</p>
<p>We believe PrestaShop Cloud will enable small and emerging businesses to quickly establish a new online store, at the lowest cost possible. We&#8217;re also taking this opportunity to rename the downloadable version of PrestaShop. Moving forward, you will see new product announcements and information for both <strong>PrestaShop Cloud</strong> and <strong>PrestaShop Download</strong>.</p>
<p>Today, we&#8217;re also launching a totally revamped <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/">website for PrestaShop</a> with a new look and feel that reflects our ambitions: clear, straightforward, simple, easy. I hope you will love it as much as we do. Our forum, which is the epicenter of community interactions, remains a very important part of this new website.</p>
<p>All of this would not be possible without your continuous support and contributions. On behalf of the 120+ talented employees at PrestaShop, I would like to thank you. We&#8217;re looking forward to another great year filled with innovation, community collaboration and ecommerce success. I would love to have your feedback, you&#8217;re welcome to contact me directly, <a href="mailto:bl@prestashop.com">bl@prestashop.com</a>.</p>
<p>All the best,</p>
<p>Bruno Leveque, PrestaShop Founder</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-for-everyone/">Ecommerce For Everyone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-for-everyone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEO for Ecommerce Website Redesign</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-ecommerce-website-redesign/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-ecommerce-website-redesign/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 13:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gary Le Masson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>So you’re planning a website redesign. Maybe you’re migrating from one platform to another or upgrading from an old version of your current ecommerce software. In either case, you’re probably up to your ears in fonts and photos, but you can’t forget about your SEO ranking. To be sure the new version of your online [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-ecommerce-website-redesign/">SEO for Ecommerce Website Redesign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So you’re planning a website redesign. Maybe you’re migrating from one platform to another or upgrading from an old version of your current ecommerce software. In either case, you’re probably up to your ears in fonts and photos, but you can’t forget about your SEO ranking.</p>
<p>To be sure the new version of your online store maintains your current SEO position, you need to prepare a little before you let your developer go to town. Specifically, you’ll need to think about <strong>structure</strong> and <strong>301 redirection</strong>.</p>
<p>In this article, we explain what a site migration is and how to prepare for it, so you have a smooth, successful redesign experience.</p>
<p><span id="more-19435"></span></p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">Who needs to read this article?</h4>
<p>The following advice is aimed primarily at merchants who already have an ecommerce site and are undertaking a redesign.</p>
<p>This article is <strong>not aimed at merchants changing their store domain name</strong>. The SEO work required for that is different.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">What is site migration?</h4>
<p>Site migration simply means transferring your old site to a new site. If you take the time to develop structure and plan ahead for 301 redirects, you’ll have a smoother transition with the following benefits:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Direct traffic to your old pages will be automatically redirected to your new website.</li>
<li>Links to pages on your old store will not lead to 404 errors.</li>
<li>You guarantee the continuity of your site SEO, which means you’ll hardly notice any drop in traffic after migration.</li>
</ul>
<h2>A little structure</h2>
<p>Before going any further, we suggest you read this article on <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">creating an &#8216;SEO friendly&#8217; structure for an ecommerce site</a>.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">Designing the structure of your new online store</h4>
<p>A site redesign is the perfect moment to reassess categories and determine which should be kept in the new version of your site and which should be eliminated. The idea is to keep what works and rethink the areas that don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>The whole point of redesigning your store is to improve upon your old store, so don’t remove categories that bring in SEO traffic and sales. You must recreate those categories in your new store in addition to developing other areas.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">Improve existing site structure</h4>
<p>Here are some places to find inspiration:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Take a look at your competitors&#8217; stores. What are they doing right? Carry out a simple benchmarking project and note what works in terms of SEO. Resist the urge to copy and paste. Good SEO demands original content</li>
<li>Revisit your initial semantic analysis and look for more <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">keywords to target.</a></li>
<li>For merchants who already use AdWords campaigns, <a href="https://www.google.com/analytics/web/template?uid=fEb3DNQXT_-2j8aKs0I9MQ" target="_blank">this report</a> may also be useful. It corresponds to keywords typed by your visitors via AdWords, and not keywords that have been paid for.</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">Google Analytics: think of it as a housewarming gift</h4>
<p>Okay, so you’ve done some surfing and revisited your initial keywords. You know you need to change some categories, but what should you replace them with? And how will you know if they’re better than what you already have?</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.google.com/analytics/web/template?uid=fEb3DNQXT_-2j8aKs0I9MQ" target="_blank">SEO Ecommerce report by PrestaShop</a> (Click on the link to add the report)</p>
<h2>“This page is no longer at this address”</h2>
<p>So you’ve built the foundation for your new store. Now you need to let the world know where it is. Enter the <strong>301 redirect</strong>.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">What are 301 redirects?</h4>
<p>When you move house and you want the post office to forward your mail to your new address, you fill out a form that looks something like this:</p>
<p style="text-align: center">Old postal address -&gt; New postal address</p>
<p>You have to do the same thing when you move your site, only it’s called a <strong>301 redirect</strong>. When a web page changes URL, you have to tell your server so that all searches can be directed to the new URL:</p>
<p style="text-align: center">Old URL -&gt; 301 redirect -&gt; New URL</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">When is a 301 redirect necessary?</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>When an old page disappears entirely&#8211;redirect this page to your home page.</li>
<li>When a page changes URL address&#8211;you need to redirect the old URL to the new URL.</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">When is a 301 redirect not necessary?</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>When a URL remains the same in the old and new versions of your site.</li>
<li>When a new page is created within your new structure which did not exist before.</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">How to put 301 redirects into place:</h4>
<p><strong>Redirect page by page.</strong> This creates a link between your old structure and the new website. It’s more precise for Google, and it provides a smoother SEO transition.</p>
<p><strong>Redirect all old URLs to your new ecommerce website home page.</strong> This isn’t the most SEO-friendly option, but it’s more appropriate when you have many URLs to migrate or there are no new equivalents for obsolete pages.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">How to prepare for 301 redirects</h4>
<p>Before your technical team can get to work, you need to prepare your URLs. Here’s how:</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">1. Identify all your site URLs</h4>
<p>Find your site URLs, old and new using a crawler such as <a href="http://home.snafu.de/tilman/xenulink.html" target="_blank">Xenu</a> (free) or <a href="http://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/" target="_blank">Screaming Frog SEO</a> (paid).</p>
<p>These tools give you access to the list of URLs from your old and new e-commerce websites and make it easy to export them to an Excel spreadsheet.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19436" alt="301 type" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/01/301-type.png" width="720" height="132" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">2. Link the two sites</h4>
<p>Display the list of URLs from your former site in one column. These URLs must either be redirected to the new equivalent URL or to the home page.</p>
<p>List the new URLs in a second column.</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">3. Integrating the 301s</h4>
<p>If you’re a developer with expert experience in SEO, then by all means integrate the .htaccess file for your new store. Otherwise, I highly recommend that you <strong>call on the expertise of an <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">SEO expert or developer</a>.</strong></p>
<h2>The big day has arrived</h2>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">When you’re ready to launch your new store:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Place your site under maintenance using the 503 code</li>
<li>Publish your new website (containing the 301 redirects in the .htaccess file)</li>
<li>Remove the maintenance code to activate your site.</li>
<li>Test the 301s immediately by typing an old URL; you should be automatically redirected to the new URL.</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember to verify that the http header sent by your server to the old URL is actually the 301 code (with this tool for <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/live-http-headers/iaiioopjkcekapmldfgbebdclcnpgnlo?hl=en" target="_blank">Chrome</a> or <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-us/firefox/addon/live-http-headers/" target="_blank">Firefox</a>).</p>
<p>You have successfully completed your migration!</p>
<p>Be aware that <strong>302 codes are not the same as 301 codes</strong>. They are temporary redirects that don’t transmit SEO information. Make sure your developer is aware of this too!</p>
<h4 style="color: #76b32a">Was this article helpful?</h4>
<p>I had the idea for writing this article at a trade show where I met a PrestaShop merchant who was migrating his site and wasn’t aware of 301 redirects.</p>
<p>If you have questions, issues or ideas for SEO articles that you would like to see addressed in 2015, please tweet us <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">@PrestaShop</a> on Twitter or visit our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>Also feel free to ask any questions about this article in the comments section below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-ecommerce-website-redesign/">SEO for Ecommerce Website Redesign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-ecommerce-website-redesign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
